John Ludena

Creative Front-end Developer

john@boldpixelmedia.com

Summary

My name is John Ludena and I've been building websites and web applications professionally for over 6 years – the last 3 working as an independent freelance contractor.

In that time, I've built countless web properties for companies ranging from brand-new startups – all the way to large corporations. I've not only gotten the chance to work with some extremely talented teams, but also learn from some smart and savvy business owners.

It's been one hell of a ride so far.

I'm currently looking for a change of pace in 2016 and looking to join a new team full-time.

Looking for a talented front-end developer who also has an eye for great design? I might just be the right person to join your team. Shoot me a message and let's start a conversation today.

Experience

Freelance Designer & Front-end Developer at Bold Pixel Media

January 2013 - Present (3 years 8 months)

I've always had a little bit of an entrepreneurial spirit and after working in a full-time career for nearly 3 years, I decided to take a chance and venture out on my own – so I started my own design studio called Bold Pixel Media.

In the last few years, I've had the amazing opportunity to work with some of Houston's top companies; including the #1 advertising agency in the city: Lopez Negrete Communications.

I've learned a lifetime of valuable lessons working on my own these past 3 years. However, truth be told, I'm a little bit tired of dealing with all the things that come with working on your own (such as constantly looking for new business, billing customers, managing my expenses and taxes, etc) and would much rather go back to working as part of a team and using 100% of my energy and focus into being creative and building things for the web.

Web Producer Contractor at PreCash

August 2015 - January 2016 (6 months)

I recently had the pleasure of working with the PreCash team to build a new website that would reflect the shift in their bill payment business for 2016 and beyond.

In addition to our re-design efforts, I was also in charge of making updates to their original site, as well as their older "legacy" product websites. Other daily duties included managing their PPC campaigns, optimizing certain pages for SEO, and creating and sending out email campaigns with important announcements to their customers.

One of the biggest accomplishments during my time at PreCash was the successful development and deployment of the new PreCash.com. Even after setting an aggressive deadline of less than 10 days, we were able to build and launch the new website to the world without any issues and shattered all expectations. The end result is a new, laser-focused web presence that reflects PreCash's new business goals for 2016 and acts as a much-improved lead-generation hub for their sales team.

Ecommerce Developer & Webmaster Contractor at Lopez Negrete Communications

November 2013 - June 2015 (1 year 8 months)

I was incredibly lucky to get the opportunity back in 2013 to work with Lopez Negrete Communications (LNC) – the top advertising agency in Houston – to build a new e-commerce presence for one of their subsidiary companies: Blue Leaf Houston.

Blue Leaf is lifestyle boutique that specializes in wedding gifts for soon-to-be brides. The project involved not only building a fully-functional store, but also integrating a third party's gift-registry software that would work with the chosen shopping cart.

I am very proud to say that I still work closely with the Blue Leaf Team (and LNC) to maintain the website, provide consultant services, and/or tech support when necessary.

Front-end Developer Contractor at FuelFX, Inc.

April 2013 - June 2014 (1 year 3 months)

FuelFX is a growing company that's doing some exciting things in the fields of Augmented Reality (AR) and Digital Marketing for the Oil & Gas industry. They've been featured in Forbes Magazine, the Houston Chronicle, and other large publications.

I was initially hired as a contractor to help build a strong Web Development department that would further compliment FFX marketing efforts on the web. During my time at the company, our web team grew quickly to over 10 people, landing big name clients as well as national design awards.

Graphic & Web Designer at Innovative Turnaround Controls

February 2010 - January 2013 (3 years)

ITC is a project controls company that caters specifically to the Energy sector. Not only do they provide highly trained personnel for refineries, but also build software products for a variety of of big names in Oil & Gas through one of their subsidiary companies, Toadfly Technologies.

I joined the ITC team to help them with their marketing and branding efforts for their multiple companies, including all printed marketing materials, trade show booths, product websites, and software products.

Working as a new member of their marketing team, I helped re-do all of the marketing materials that ITC and their subsidiaries use today on a day-to-day basis for sales presentations, trade shows, as well as their specialized suite of web applications for the Energy industry.

Languages

Spanish

English

(Native or bilingual proficiency) (Native or bilingual proficiency)

Skills & Expertise

Web Design

Graphics

Adobe Creative Suite

Photoshop

Graphic Design

Web Development

WordPress

CMS

Dreamweaver

Layout

SEO

Illustrator

CSS

Logo Design

Posters

Corporate Identity

Brochures

InDesign

Typography

Illustration

Joomla

Advertising

Node.js

MongoDB

JavaScript

React.js

Backbone.js

Express.js

jQuery

User Interface Design

User Experience Design

SASS

Github

Heroku

PHP

Education

The Iron Yard

Front-end Engineering, Computer Programming, Specific Applications, 2016 - 2016

University of Houston

2004 - 2009

Texas Tech University

Electrical Engineering, 2003 - 2004

John Ludena

Creative Front-end Developer

john@boldpixelmedia.com



1 person has recommended John

"John Ludena has an attitude to strive for whatever goals he sets or are placed before him. He gives himself to the projects that are placed in front of him and does all he can to accomplish them. His skills are amazing and what makes them even better is his unique eye of creativity that allows him to think outside the box. His designs and creations are fresh and well designed giving an unparalleled professional look and feel. He is a great co-worker, employee, friend, leader!"

— Thomas Trevino, worked directly with John at Innovative Turnaround Controls

Contact John on LinkedIn